<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Thomas Stachl]]></title>
  <link href="http://stachl.me/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stachl.me/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-07T13:01:18+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://stachl.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Stachl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another turning point]]></title>
    <link href="http://stachl.me/blog/2012/09/04/another-turning-point.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T20:44:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stachl.me/blog/2012/09/04/another-turning-point</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Eventually everyone has to decide whether to live his life according to a predefined course
or to take action and pursuit a life of happiness and joy but also downfalls and hardship. 
Are you walking the safe road or are you choosing a live of adventure and unknown? For me it
was a very personal decision I made two years ago - I started to live my life in the pursuit
of my dreams.</p>

<p>You can probably ask every person who spent time with me and they’ll all tell you that my
dream is and was to live in the United States. But two years ago when I started this journey
I had to make sure that it really was what I wanted for myself, so I decided to quit my job 
and become a freelancer.</p>

<p>As a freelancer you have certain privileges, like working from wherever and whenever you want.
You can decide to work 4 hours a day or 12 hours, it’s up to you to find a company to work for
or projects to work on. So that was a perfect fit for my US trial run. I started to work for
a San Francisco based company developing web services.</p>

<p>A few months in I was able to afford my first trip to Los Angeles so I bought my tickets and
even had a few hundred dollars left on my bank account for incidentals. It was around the
15th of June 2010 and I still remember as if it was yesterday. My mom gave me a ride to the
airport in Munich and I took off. After a quick flight to London and a brief overlay I boarded
a big Boing which should take me all the way over the Atlantic ocean to the Pacific.</p>

<p>It must have been around 7pm when I finally arrived and I got into the bus to Union Station
where I was supposed to meet a guy I met on <a href="http://www.couchsurfing.org/">CouchSurfing.org</a> - 
but he never showed. Something must have happened, I thought. While still whishing for the best
I found myself a cab and gave the drive the address.</p>

<p>Even though I had this feeling of uncertainty in my stomach I was so overwhelmed by all those
new impressions, the smell, the dry LA heat in the evenings I didn’t even think about
loosing faith. And as it turned out I was right, he just forgot about my arrival time so I still
had a bed for the first few nights.</p>

<p>Cutting a really long story short - I had the best time in Los Angeles and even after three
months of not seeing my family and friends back home in Austria, I still wouldn’t want to leave.
This showed me that I was on the right track. That I should reach for the stars and continue my
quest.</p>

<p>Jumping ahead to June 2011 the 6th to be exact. Once again I found myself at the airport in
Munich saying my goodbyes to my mother and Josef. This time it wasn’t about going to the US,
I started a job with <a href="http://www.salesforce.com/">Salesforce.com</a> in their European headquarters 
in Dublin, Ireland. Salesforce is also a San Francisco based company, one of the first to use the
term cloud computing. As opposed to being a freelancer this gainful employment was always meant
to be my stepping stone to the States.</p>

<p>In those almost one and a half years I found myself growing fond of Ireland, Dublin especially
as I actually didn’t see much more than that. And with Salesforce I was even able to fly over to
San Francisco twice, I also got the opportunity to visit London and had an extended stay with our 
neighbors in Munich. Telling you all this and giving a slight hint to Forbes list of best companies 
to work for should be enough to convince you that I never regret for one second haven take up this
nine-to-five.</p>

<p>And it’s about to get even better, over the course of the last couple of months I applied for
a position as a Technical Consultant with a 100 % subsidiary of Salesforce in San Francisco.
Yes you read correctly, one of my dreams is about to come true and I’ll be able to live and
work in one of the most accomplished nations of this world. I’m going to work for
<a href="http://www.desk.com/">Desk.com</a>.</p>

<p>A new part of my life is starting in a few weeks and once again I’m overcome with joy and
happiness but also the knowledge that it doesn’t end here. Dreams are coming every night
like clockwork, I close my eyes and start imagining and everything begins again. What’s next?
I don’t know but one thing I know for sure, it’s going to be one hell of ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
