<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Development | Thomas Stachl]]></title>
  <link href="http://stachl.me/categories/development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stachl.me/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-07T13:01:18+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://stachl.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Thomas Stachl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salesforce Site and Facebook Page Tab]]></title>
    <link href="http://stachl.me/blog/2012/09/07/salesforce-site-and-facebook-page-tab.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-07T12:22:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stachl.me/blog/2012/09/07/salesforce-site-and-facebook-page-tab</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every once in a while in my job I get asked to develop an application on the <a href="http://developer.force.com/">Force.com</a>
Platform that can be included into a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/">Facebook</a> Page as a page tab. Now initially you’d
think not a problem at all we’ll just create visualforce page and put it on a site, link the
Facebook page tab app to the visualforce page and that’s it. We’ll you’re right it would be 
really that simple if you don’t need the Facebook user to sign in and be an authenticated 
portal user on the site.</p>

<p>But authentication can’t be to terrible since Spring ‘12 <a href="http://www.salesforce.com/">Salesforce</a> even offers the so
called <a href="http://blogs.developerforce.com/developer-relations/2012/01/social-single-sign-on-authentication-providers-in-spring-12.html">Social Single Sign On</a> which allows you to add Facebook as an authentication
provider in your Salesforce Organization. Still it’s not the simplest of all tasks, with all
those redirections, X-Frame and SSL policies and what not. So after the third time I tried
to hack my way around I thought why not come up with a flow that works always and package
it up for reuse.</p>

<p>My solution involved a redirection flow built in Javascript and packaged as a visualforce
Component. So here is what basically happens:</p>

<ul>
  <li>John Doe finds himself on our Facebook Page</li>
  <li>He clicks on the page tab</li>
  <li>Depending on weather John surfs using SSL or not the page tab loads the visualforce page
using the same protocol</li>
  <li>Now the first thing this script does is to test if John Doe has a valid session</li>
  <li>John Doe has never been on our visualforce page so he is redirected to the SSSO</li>
  <li>The SSSO in turn will redirect John back to Facebook so he can authenticate and authorize
our app</li>
  <li>If he does he’ll then get redirected back to SSSO which will either create a new user
or use an existing one for John</li>
  <li>SSSO knows that the request came from a Force.com Site and redirects accordingly</li>
  <li>At this stage the script will check if there is a return URL set and redirect there</li>
</ul>

<p>Now all you need to do is grab the code for the component on <a href="https://github.com/tstachl/fbookLoginRedirector">github.com/tstachl</a> and add it
to your probably empty start/redirector page: <code>&lt;c:fbookLoginRedirector loginUrl="" retUrl="" /&gt;</code>
There is an example visualforce page included and if you set this page as start page of a 
site you should be good to go.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knockout.js for Visualforce]]></title>
    <link href="http://stachl.me/blog/2012/09/04/knockout-dot-js-for-visualforce.html"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T12:21:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://stachl.me/blog/2012/09/04/knockout-dot-js-for-visualforce</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I saw an introduction video about <a href="http://knockoutjs.com/">Knockout.js</a> a javascript library
that shows sweet advantages on declarative bindings, automatic UI refresh, 
dependency tracking and templating.</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/DnhGqcKEPiM "></iframe></div></p>

<p>After watching this I realized how nice and easy you could bind data onto forms,
tables and whole templates. Immediately I thought about Visualforce and how this
could make it easier to create nice looking custom user interfaces utilizing either
Apex remote action or the Javascript toolkit.</p>

<p>My colleague a big <a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a> fan didn’t seem to be convinced at all, so the
challenge was set and I knew what I had to do.</p>

<h2 id="the-challenge">The Challenge</h2>
<p>For the first try run I wanted to find something simple and an editable grid showing
accounts (Twitter handles of accounts to be more precise) seemed to be easy enough.
The idea was to show the list of accounts with account name, a disabled checkbox to 
indicate whether or not an account had a Twitter handle and of course the Twitter 
handle itself which should be editable.</p>

<p><img src="/images/knockoutjs_visualforce_goal.png" alt="A table with accounts, twitter account indicator and the twitter handle" title="The goal!" /></p>

<h2 id="the-fun-part">The fun part</h2>
<p>So I started out with creating a Visualforce page and a controller. The only reason 
for the controller was to get a JSON encoded list of accounts and I thought that was
a fast and straight forward approach, whilst the real magic is happening in the 
Visualforce page. At least in this small example. So let’s start with the controller:</p>

<pre class="prettyprint lang-java linenums"><code>public class KnockoutController
{
  public KnockoutController()
  {}
  public String getAccountsJson()
  {
    return JSON.serialize((List&lt;Account&gt;)[SELECT Id, Name, TwitterHandle__c FROM Account]);
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>As you can see there is one getter for the account list and that’s it. The Visualforce
page on the other hand contains 64 lines of markup and code. I think most of it is 
self explanatory but I added a few comments just in case.</p>

<pre class="prettyprint lang-html linenums"><code>&lt;apex:page controller="KnockoutController" tabStyle="Account" &gt;
  &lt;apex:includeScript value="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/knockout/2.1.0/knockout-min.js" /&gt;
  &lt;apex:sectionHeader title="Knockout.js + Salesforce.com" subtitle="Like?" /&gt;
  
  &lt;!-- The Template --&gt;
  &lt;table width="100%"&gt;
    &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Account Name&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Has Twitter&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Twitter Handle&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody data-bind="foreach: accounts"&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td data-bind="text: name"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;
          &lt;input type="checkbox" disabled="disabled" data-bind="checked: has_twitter" /&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td data-bind="event: { dblclick: toggle_edit }"&gt;
          &lt;span data-bind="visible: !is_editing(), text: twitter"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;input data-bind="visible: is_editing, value: twitter, event: { blur: toggle_edit }" /&gt;
        &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;

  &lt;script&gt;
    !function() {
      // The Account model
      function Account(options) {
        this.id = options.Id || ''
        this.name = options.Name || ''
        this.twitter = ko.observable(options.TwitterHandle__c || '')
        this.is_editing = ko.observable(false)
        
        // computed observable tells us if we have a twitter handle
        this.has_twitter = ko.computed(function() {
          return !!this.twitter()
        }, this)

        // the function to toggle between editing and viewing
        this.toggle_edit = function(account) {
          account.is_editing(!account.is_editing())
        }
      }

      // all of the magic happens in the model
      // the viewModel just holds the accounts array
      view_model = {
        accounts: ko.observableArray([])
      }

      // here we have our {!accountsJson} mapped and transformed to
      // account objects
      view_model.accounts(ko.utils.arrayMap({!accountsJson}, function(account) {
        return new Account(account)
      }))

      // last but not least we need to apply all bindings
      ko.applyBindings(view_model)
    }()
  &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/apex:page&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>As you can see it’s fairly simple to create a nice observable and dynamic user interface 
using <a href="http://knockoutjs.com/">Knockout.js</a>. Even-though my colleague would still tell me it’s faster to build
this functionality in <a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a> (and he might even be right), this weekend I’m going
to show you why I consider Knockout.js a really good idea and how fast and straight forward
you can create a nice and clean Salesforce Ideas clone.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
